my name is Christophe fuller I work for
我的名字是克里斯托弗·富勒
pivotal as an engineer in the spring
在春季起关键作用
data team basically focusing on these
数据团队基本上专注于这些
four abstractions for MongoDB readies a
MongoDB的四个抽象准备就绪
solar thank you value stuff but I also
太阳能谢谢您重视的东西，但我也
do changes on the GPA molecule as well
也会改变GPA分子
as the newly introduced key value one
作为新引入的关键值之一
and we're gonna talk today about a very
今天我们要谈论一个非常
specific group of Spring data modules
特定组的Spring数据模块
namely those that you can use for search
即可以用于搜索的那些
full-text search or and that's what
全文搜索，或者就是这样
basically makes up the agenda so if we
基本上构成了议程，所以如果我们
take a quick look at the history of
快速浏览一下的历史
search within the Java ecosystem it
在Java生态系统中搜索
basically turned out to have started in
基本上已经开始
1999 when Lucy was initially released so
1999年，露西最初发行时，
all seen is up till today the core
直到今天为止，所有可见的核心
technology for most search engines that
大多数搜索引擎的技术
are out there for for Java and so
在那里有Java等等
basically it contains all the the stuff
基本上它包含了所有的东西
you need to analyze your tags to
您需要分析标签以
categorize it to store it in your in the
将其分类存储在您的
proper way and most of the more modern
正确的方法和大多数更现代的
search technologies are built on it
搜索技术基于此
so basically 2004 the Apache Solr was
所以基本上2004年的Apache Solr是
released - this added basically a server
发布-这基本上增加了服务器
component around below scene search
场景下搜索周围的组件
technology so up til that from that time
从那时起直到现在
on we were basically able to access our
我们基本上可以访问我们的
search wire a dedicated component within
搜索线内的专用组件
our infrastructure we were able to talk
我们能够谈论的基础设施
to the search engine wire rest like
到搜索引擎线休息像
interface over HTTP we have various
通过HTTP的接口，我们有各种
input and output formats so solar was
输入和输出格式是太阳能
capable of capable of dealing with or
有能力处理或
XML CSV and all that stuff and it has a
XML CSV等所有内容，
Curie a P I that you could use where an
居里PI，您可以在其中使用
HTTP request so this was pretty awesome
HTTP请求，所以这很棒
and
和
there were several features that haven't
有些功能还没有
been covered in leucine so far like
到目前为止被亮氨酸覆盖
faceting we'll come to that later
方面，我们稍后会谈到
that we're only implemented in solar so
我们只在太阳能中实现
it took quite some time till those two
直到那两个人花了很长时间
project basically projects basically
基本项目基本项目
join forces and merged more or less and
联合起来或多或少地合并在一起
that was the time that for example
例如那个时候
faceting got merged into the leucine
刻面并入亮氨酸
core capabilities so solar has been
太阳能的核心能力
around for for over ten years by now and
到现在已经有十多年了
in 2010 there was some competition on
在2010年，
the searcher market for Java with the
Java搜索市场
release of elastic search and this was a
释放弹性搜索，这是一个
kind of good thing because it brought
一件好事，因为它带来了
competition and elasticsearch solved
竞争和弹性搜索解决
some of the problems that haven't been
一些尚未解决的问题
addressed too far by solar itself so in
由太阳能本身解决了太多问题，所以在
2010 what you have was basically one
2010年您基本上拥有的是
search server if you were using solar
搜索服务器（如果您使用的是太阳能）
and local clusters so if your server was
和本地集群，因此如果您的服务器是
down you had to somehow deal with it on
下来，你不得不以某种方式处理它
your own and you weren't able to cluster
你自己的，你无法集群
it or shard data and that was something
它或分片数据，那是什么
elastic search came up with so it was
弹性搜索出来了，所以
pretty easy to spin up a cluster of
旋转起来很容易
search servers that were connected to
连接到的搜索服务器
attack each other and did the charting
互相攻击并绘制图表
for you and the automatic failover which
为您和自动故障转移
is pretty awesome so the solar community
非常棒，所以太阳能社区
had to do something about it and this is
必须对此做些事情，这是
nice to see that by now the clustering
很高兴看到现在集群
capabilities though differently
能力不同
implemented our part of solar as well so
也实施了我们的太阳能事业
you see the competition brought
你看到比赛带来了
something to for us all for the
给我们所有人的东西
community and since we have a dedicated
社区，因为我们有专门的
spring date MongoDB module and MongoDB
春季日期MongoDB模块和MongoDB
released with its 2.6 version search
与2.6版本搜索一起发布
integration within their store we're
整合到他们的商店中
going to have a look at that as well
也会去看看
though I must admit the search
虽然我必须承认搜索
capabilities within MongoDB are a not
MongoDB中的功能不是
based on the scene so they did their own
根据现场，所以他们做了自己的
thing and be MongoDB is no search server
事，成为MongoDB不是搜索服务器
by definition so the first two or solar
根据定义，所以前两个或太阳能
Angela
安吉拉
search a fully-fledged search service
搜索成熟的搜索服务
with all the capital k p-- abilities you
拥有全部资本k p
will want to have for billing your your
想要为您的帐单付款
applications while mama DB just offers a
应用程序，而妈妈数据库只是提供了一个
full-text search as part of its database
全文搜索作为其数据库的一部分
so there is a distinction in there so
所以那里有一个区别
please don't don't mix up things and go
请不要把事情混在一起走
out of this session and say hey mama DB
结束本次会议，然后说妈妈数据库
is our full text search engine that's
是我们的全文搜索引擎
not the case but you have the
并非如此，但您有
capabilities in there good so in today's
那里的功能很好，今天
session as i already said we're not
会议，正如我已经说过的，我们不是
going to cover internals of the scene or
将要覆盖场景的内部或
a dick - too deep into that but we'll
鸡巴-太深了，但我们会
have a look at how we can do full text
看看我们如何做全文
search with MongoDB
用MongoDB搜索
with Apache Solr and elastic search and
与Apache Solr和弹性搜索以及
how we can use these bring data
我们如何使用这些带来的数据
abstractions on top of those
在这些之上的抽象
technologies and what it means for us
技术及其对我们的意义
when we use it so the potential pitfalls
当我们使用它时，潜在的陷阱
and all that stuff but before we start
还有所有这些东西，但在我们开始之前
what is this thing we search basically
我们基本上搜索的是什么东西
all about I mean in my opinion search is
关于我的全部意思是我认为搜索是
a pretty simple requirement I mean it's
一个非常简单的要求，我的意思是
I want to find my data quick and easy
我想快速轻松地找到我的数据
and I have seen applications that failed
而且我看到了失败的应用程序
not because they were really implemented
不是因为他们真的被实施了
or badly tested or I had parts or
或测试不良，或者我有零件或
missing features but simply because they
缺少功能，只是因为它们
were unusable because users weren't able
之所以无法使用，是因为用户无法
to find their data so there is a kind of
找到他们的数据，所以有一种
funny story when I went to a local book
我去读一本本地书时的有趣故事
store a few weeks ago in my hometown and
几周前在我的家乡存储
I was asking for a specific book and I
我当时要一本特定的书，我
was telling them the author in the title
在标题中告诉他们作者
and the guy at the at the counter
还有柜台的家伙
basically told me oh wait let me just
基本上告诉我哦，等等，让我
quickly up open Google and search it in
快速打开Goog​​le并在其中搜索
there and then copy the ice P n so
在那里，然后复制冰P n因此
basically the book number into their
基本上把书号放进去
very own system because this is faster
自己的系统，因为这更快
than searching within their own system
比在自己的系统中搜索
so well in my opinion that can't be the
我认为很好
case and if you have let's
情况下，如果您让我们
a sensable later so if you're have a
明智的选择，所以如果你有一个
call center application dealing with
呼叫中心应用程序处理
thousands of customer numbers first
首先是数千个客户编号
names last name sensitive data you
命名您的姓氏敏感数据
cannot just go on to google and search
不能仅仅去谷歌搜索
the person in the urn thing could be
骨灰盒里的人可能是
some internal ID into your your system
一些内部ID进入您的系统
so you get to do something about it
所以你可以做点什么
without potentially killing the database
没有潜在地杀死数据库
by executing whatever what have you SQL
通过执行任何您拥有的SQL
statement against it basically doing a
针对它的声明基本上是在做
full full table scan on or even worse
全表扫描或什至更糟
multiple full table scans so it's a
多次全表扫描，所以这是一个
simple requirement I want you to find my
简单的要求，我想让你找到我的
data I want to find it in a human
我想在人类中找到的数据
readable way that's also very important
可读的方式也很重要
I don't want you to know about some
我不想让你知道一些
expression language I have to understand
我必须了解的表达语言
before it can even enter my search term
在输入我的搜索字词之前
I want to have it like like Google has
我想要像Google一样拥有它
it that's that's the requirement I want
这就是我想要的要求
to type in something I can easily
输入我可以轻松输入的内容
understand so it's a pretty simple
明白，这很简单
requirement in my opinion but the thing
我认为是必需品
with simple requirements is that this
简单的要求是
can be implemented pretty far pretty
可以实现很漂亮
pretty easily but the thing is people
很容易，但问题是人
make mistakes and I also want to work my
犯错误，我也想努力
search if I if the user makes mistakes
搜索我是否用户出错
so this is something a search engine
所以这是一个搜索引擎
should be capable of so if I have a typo
应该有能力，如果我有错字
in my search query I still want to do to
在我的搜索查询中，我仍然想做
have it to do the right thing for me I
有它为我做正确的事
want to find the documents though I made
我想找文件
a mistake
错误
so I'm sorry a pretty simple requirement
所以对不起一个非常简单的要求
can turn out into a really really
可以变成一个真正的
complex solution so this is basically
复杂的解决方案，所以这基本上是
the algorithm for the 11 steam distance
11个蒸汽距离的算法
that is used to calculate the distance
用于计算距离
between words based on the distance of
字距之间的距离
each character to the other oh thank god
每个字符都给对方哦，感谢上帝
there's much more smarter people than me
有比我更聪明的人
who provided us with some kind of
谁给我们提供了某种
abstraction so this is basically all at
抽象，所以这基本上就是
the elasticsearch representation of the
的弹性搜索表示
levenshtein distance algorithm in a real
实际中的levenshtein距离算法
in a developer readable way so you have
以开发人员可读的方式
you need to learn some syntax and then
您需要学习一些语法，然后
you can go on and make use of of the
您可以继续使用
work someone did for us thankfully great
有人为我们所做的工作值得庆幸的是
having that said I want to quote Milford
话虽如此，我想引用米尔福德
huh a little bit because this is the
有点，因为这是
more or less the model for this session
或多或少的本届会议的模型
you need to understand one level of
您需要了解一个层次的
abstraction beneath are the one which
下面的抽象是
you're working on so basically we have
你正在努力，所以基本上
this solar elasticsearch MongoDB
这个太阳弹性搜索MongoDB
abstraction around those complex
那些复杂的抽象
algorithms within the database or data
数据库或数据中的算法
store that will be work for us then we
商店将为我们工作，然后我们
got the driver for that specific store
找到了该特定商店的驱动程序
as another level of abstraction that
作为另一个抽象层次
mainly offers really direct capabilities
主要提供真正的直接功能
so I have to know about the the query
所以我必须了解查询
language in there and all that stuff and
语言以及所有这些东西
on top of that we get the swing data
最重要的是，我们获得了挥杆数据
repository template and a repository
存储库模板和存储库
abstraction so there is quite a lot of
抽象，所以有很多
layers in between what's happening in
在发生的事情之间
the store actually and what the API you
商店实际以及您使用什么API
get exposed to and so we'll try to have
接触，所以我们将尝试
a look at this tak in between so you
看看这之间的德
understand what happens in in the
了解在发生了什么
specific part of of those components
这些组件的特定部分
okay
好的
Oh anyone who doesn't know what spring
哦，谁不知道春天
daters all about or hasn't used it so
约会者关于或未使用过的所有信息
far oh yeah a few hands okay uh I'll go
远哦，是的，几只手，好吧，我去
over that real quick so this as this is
在那真正的快速，所以这是
an introduction introduction session so
简介会
spring data is basically composed of
弹簧数据基本上是由
several modules so we have the the core
几个模块，所以我们有核心
set of modules which is commands which
模块集是命令
holds common types that we use in the
拥有我们在
different story implementations like a
不同的故事实现，例如
page the tolds contents and tells you
页面告诉的内容，并告诉你
about is there a next page in previous
关于上一页是否有下一页
page and all that stuff we got
页面以及我们得到的所有东西
implementations for JPA with the several
JPA的几个实现
cheapy providers like hibernate eclipse
像冬食这样的廉价供应商
link and all that stuff we got support
链接以及我们获得支持的所有东西
from MongoDB with both drive aversions
从两个驱动器厌恶的MongoDB
to dot 12.3 i guess was the latest until
点12.3我猜是最新的
three the oh well version line
三行版哦
we got neo4j we got solar gem fire the
我们有neo4j我们有太阳能宝石火
odd one out is is rest because it's not
奇怪的是休息，因为它不是
really a store abstraction but more how
真正的商店抽象，但更多
to expose a repository is into HTTP
将存储库公开到HTTP
resources we got ready sent the key
我们准备好的资源发送了密钥
value module there's also a lot of
价值模块也有很多
community modules and work going on
社区模块和正在进行的工作
there because there is a couch base
在那里，因为有沙发底座
there is the elasticsearch module I'm
有我的elasticsearch模块
going to present you today which is
今天要向您介绍
actually not maintained by us but by the
实际上不是我们维护的，而是
community itself so there's there's a
社区本身，所以有一个
bunch of guys in London who liked
一群喜欢伦敦的家伙
elasticsearch a lot and who liked the
elasticsearch很多，谁喜欢
the idea of spring data a lot so that is
spring data 的想法很多，这就是
basically sat there and implemented that
基本上坐在那里并实施
stuff and it's really cool to see all
东西，看到所有东西真的很酷
those community projects evolve and grow
这些社区项目不断发展壮大
and there is one for Cassandra as well
卡桑德拉（Cassandra）也有一个
and as I said there are many community
正如我所说的，有很多社区
projects some are incubating currently
一些正在孵化的项目
just want to create theirs aerospike
只是想创造他们的航拍
with those guys did a lot of work
和那些家伙做了很多工作
recently and there's even one poor
最近甚至有一个穷人
request open for a spring data
请求打开弹簧数据
repository abstraction for hazel caste
榛树种姓的存储库抽象
cos that's the world also offers or it's
因为世界也提供了cos，或者
on query language so it's kind of
关于查询语言，所以有点
natural fit but we're gonna have a look
天作之合，但我们来看看
at those three and as you saw there are
在那三个，就像你看到的那样
many many modules within the spring data
弹簧数据中的许多模块
releases and we basically try to group
发布，我们基本上尝试分组
those releases together so that you
这些版本一起发布，以便您
don't have to deal with the different
不必面对不同
versions of the modules because those
模块的版本，因为那些
all of those evolve on their own pace
所有这些都按照自己的节奏发展
and we don't force them to upgrade to
并且我们不强迫他们升级到
come on the version line so basically
基本上在版本行上
there's I think elasticsearch is one of
我认为elasticsearch是其中之一
three currently while so as 1.6 and JPA
目前有3个，例如1.6和JPA
is 1.9 I hope
我希望是1.9
remember that correctly but we tried to
记住正确，但是我们尝试
group them together and do some semantic
将它们组合在一起并进行一些语义
versioning and we basically named our
版本控制，我们基本上将其命名为
releases after famous persons in our
在我们的名人之后释放
industry so we started in 2013 with
行业，所以我们从2013年开始
Aurora Babbage called Dijkstra events
Aurora Babbage称为Dijkstra事件
the follow release in 2015 and Gosling
2015年和Gosling的后续发布
is currently the latest release and the
是当前的最新版本，
next one will be named after Grace
下一个将以格蕾丝（Grace）的名字命名
Hopper
料斗
and it's about about to go GA is someone
而且快要走了
in November if everything works out out
如果一切顺利，在十一月
as its planned and to make it really
按照计划并使其真正实现
easy for you to pick up diversions and
方便您领取转移
so that you don't have to remember all
这样您就不必记住所有
of those versions we offer you something
这些版本中，我们为您提供了一些东西
that's called the release bomb it's
这就是所谓的释放炸弹
basically a pom file holding all those
基本上是保存所有这些的pom文件
all version numbers as properties so you
所有版本号都作为属性，因此您
can later on override it and all you
以后可以覆盖它，你也可以
have to basically do is enter the
基本要做的就是输入
artefact ID which is spring data -
人工数据ID（是 spring data ）-
spring - data that's released train and
春天-发布的数据火车和
an error at the Gosling - release or as
Gosling发生错误-发布或
r1 or the Fowler release the one you
r1或Fowler释放您
choose and then go on and add that stuff
选择然后继续添加该东西
to your dependency management section in
到您的依赖性管理部分
in maven and you can basically go on and
在行家，你基本上可以继续
oops
哎呀
there you go and the courrier dependency
你去那里和快递员的依赖
dependencies without having to worry
依赖关系而不必担心
about explicitly explicitly defining the
关于明确定义
abortion diversion for let's say spring
人工流产，比如说春天
the direst web MVC and MongoDB because
最重要的Web MVC和MongoDB是因为
those versions that work together are
可以一起使用的版本是
already defined in the release pump
在释放泵中已经定义
so let's have a quick look at how spring
让我们快速看一下春天
data actually works so we have several
数据实际上有效，所以我们有几个
layers of abstractions so very very low
抽象层次如此之低
very low Lehrer is the template
Lehrer非常低的模板
abstraction as you may know from the
您可能从中知道的抽象
JDBC template or the JMS template or
JDBC模板或JMS模板或
what have you in Spring Framework so
您在Spring Framework中拥有什么
it's it's pretty easy to find your way
这很容易找到你的方式
around if you have used one of the
如果您使用过其中一种
others already and this gives you
已经有人，这给你
basically access to the lower lay low
基本上进入低位
level API of the specific stores so this
特定商店的级别API，因此
is something we try to to do with spring
这是我们尝试与春天做的事情
data is not to shield you from using
数据并不能阻止您使用
native store api's so you can use them
本地存储API，因此您可以使用它们
if you want to but we try to offer you
如果您愿意，但我们尝试为您提供
higher abstractions but you still can
更高的抽象度，但您仍然可以
use the lower ones so this is basically
使用较低的，所以基本上
a do a setting DD profiling level for a
为a做一个DD配置文件级别设置
MongoDB database to your debug mode so
MongoDB数据库进入调试模式，因此
lock everything on top of those low
将所有东西锁定在那些低点之上
level templates we get the repository
级别模板，我们获取存储库
implementation which is basically that
实施基本上就是
part we have that does all the DES
我们拥有的部分可以完成所有DES
proxying for you to get to get an actual
代理您获得实际
or store specific spring data repository
或存储特定的Spring数据存储库
implementation so that this is the part
实施，所以这是一部分
that lets you define just an interface
让您只定义一个接口
so that you don't have to write your
这样您就不必写您的
data access code all over again
数据访问代码再次
so we offer you basically the
所以我们基本上为您提供
abstractions for crowd repository paging
人群存储库分页的抽象
and storage repository and with that you
和存储库，并与您一起
basically get all the stuff you you
基本上得到你所有的东西
naturally expect from there so you get
自然地期望从那里，所以你得到
save operations you've got to find all
保存您必须查找的所有操作
operations you can find something by an
您可以通过操作找到一些东西
ID and of course you can be eat all the
身份证，当然你可以吃饱了
stuff again so there's the neat all as
东西再次，所以有整洁的作为
well but I wouldn't use that too
好吧，但我也不会用
frequently actually and the cool part is
实际上，最酷的部分是
oh the last part
哦，最后一部分
oh I'm showing you in this really really
哦，我真的向你展示了
short spring data introduction there's
简短的 spring data 介绍
there's much more to learn
还有更多的东西要学习
and to see but there's dedicated talks
看看，但有专门的讲座
out there in the web you can watch or
在网上您可以观看或
see where you just step by later on and
看看以后您一步一步走，然后
we'll have a chat so basically what we
我们将聊天，基本上
offer you as well is the derived finder
也为您提供了派生的发现者
methods so what we do here is we analyze
方法，所以我们在这里要做的是分析
at startup time the method names you put
在启动时，您放置的方法名称
into your repository analyze the return
进入您的存储库分析收益
types and figure out for you what it
类型并为您弄清楚它是什么
really should look like that we are
真的应该看起来像我们
going to execute later on so find by
稍后执行，因此找到
title returning a list will basically
标题返回列表基本上
read all all documents from a MongoDB
从MongoDB中读取所有所有文档
that match a given title or you can use
匹配给定标题或您可以使用
the EDP abstraction so we provide you
EDP​​抽象，所以我们为您提供
with out-of-the-box pagination so you
开箱即用的分页功能
can basically use the page table or the
基本上可以使用页表或
page table parameter to define hey I
页表参数定义嘿我
want to get a page one with size 10 and
想要获得大小为10的第一页，
it gives you the correct result in
它给你正确的结果
return as part of page and tells you
返回页面的一部分并告诉你
either is the next one and this is by
要么是下一个，这是通过
the way the page table to use to get the
页面表用于获取的方式
next page you also can use delete by
您还可以在下一页上使用Delete by
author which will create a create a
作者将创建一个
delete query or recently we added
删除查询或最近我们添加了
support for streaming basically this is
支持流基本上是
available for 40 p.m. Modi beep where we
可在下午40点Modi哔哔声中使用
wrap our cursors so that you can make
包装我们的光标，以便您可以
use of the d-string api at each hour its
每小时使用d字符串api
stream API good so we're done with our
流API很好，所以我们完成了
really really fast introduction to
真的非常快速地介绍
spring data so let's get dirty with some
spring data ，让我们开始讨论
search technology and in order to do
搜索技术和为了做
that I'm going to be going to use a few
我将要使用一些
few terms later on I think we should
几句话以后，我认为我们应该
have a look at at least the following
至少看看以下内容
terms this is in first place what is the
术语，这首先是什么
scheme or what does the schema mean in
方案或该模式的含义
terms of search I mean schema is more or
搜索条件，我的意思是架构更多或
less the same stuff as you're used to
不太像以前那样的东西
from relational databases so it
从关系数据库中
basically tells you in which format a
基本上告诉您一种格式
given data type is
给定的数据类型是
and what to apply but there is a little
以及什么申请，但有一点
bit more when you use it research but
当您使用它进行研究时会更多
for now that will do then we'll have a
现在就可以了，我们将有一个
look at a little bit of text analysis
看一点文字分析
what does it mean how can you use it
这是什么意思
what does it look like
它是什么样子的
are there pitfalls what should I better
有陷阱我该怎么办
not do we'll have a look at what scoring
不，我们看看什么得分
and boosting is as there's a term stable
而提升是因为有一个术语稳定
and as you would look at query ver
就像您查询查询ver
versus filter query okay so let me just
与筛选器查询还可以，让我来
quickly step out of here and fire up
迅速离开这里并开火
elasticsearch in instance okay this may
例如，elasticsearch好吧，这可能
take a second or so so I'm using a
花一秒钟左右，所以我正在使用
single node elastic search search for
单节点弹性搜索搜索
this demo and I wanted to show you just
这个演示，我想向您展示
a little bit of the elastic search from
一点点的弹性搜索
configuration so what we basically have
配置，所以我们基本上有
here is a elastic search ammo that's in
这是一个弹性搜索弹药
the configuration directory of your
您的配置目录
elastic search distribution and what I
弹性搜索分布和我
did here is basically define a cluster
基本上是在定义集群
name because elastic search has the
名称是因为弹性搜索具有
capability to basically find cluster
基本找到集群的能力
nodes by itself so and by by the cluster
节点本身以及群集
name so if you don't configure it and
命名，以便您不进行配置，并且
fire up several nodes on your local
在本地启动几个节点
machine they will find each other or
机器，他们会发现彼此或
even reach out on the network which is
甚至可以通过网络
kind of bad thing on a conference
会议上的坏事
because it potentially may join some
因为它可能会加入一些
other cluster that might be around here
可能在这里的其他集群
so I give it a dedicated name and hope
所以我给它起个专用的名字和希望
that no one else has it and in order to
没有人拥有它，并且为了
make sure that really no one interferes
确保真的没有人干预
currently I also used this little friend
目前我也用过这个小朋友
down here which is called I can you
在这叫我可以吗
actually read it I'll zoom in a little
实际阅读它，我会放大一点
bit which is called Network host so this
称为网络主机的位
little friend basically limits in and
小朋友基本上限制了
outgoing connections to my local machine
与本地计算机的传出连接
just to make sure that no one interferes
只是为了确保没有人干预
and this is also helpful if you're
如果您是
working in a company and don't want to
在公司工作，不想
come your local elasticsearch connect
来你当地的elasticsearch连接
with all the others who if within the
与所有其他人，如果在
company network and there's
公司网络，还有
one more option that might sometimes be
有时可能是另一种选择
helpful and that was the cluster denote
有用的，那是集群的意思
name so by default elasticsearch when it
命名，因此默认情况下为elasticsearch
starts up picks a random Morel comic
开始选择随机的羊肚菌漫画
character name they have some connection
角色名称，他们有一些联系
in there I don't know actually what it
在那儿我实际上不知道
is about but there seem to be a thousand
即将到来，但似乎有一千
and six hundred Marvel comic characters
和六百个漫威漫画人物
and it should just picks a random name
它应该选择一个随机的名字
for it for the instance you have which
对于您拥有的实例
can be nice in some way because it's
在某种程度上可以很好，因为
kind of funny to see all the names you
看到你所有的名字真有趣
you potentially know but it's hard to
您可能知道，但很难
figure out in logs which note this had
在日志中找出其中有
this name at that time belong to before
当时这个名字属于
it crashed because it potentially has
它崩溃了，因为它可能有
another name when it starts up so I
启动时的另一个名字，所以我
would recommend to set this but for now
建议设置这个，但是暂时
I have let me see oh it's already
我让我看看哦已经
started so let's have a look at at the
开始，让我们来看看
dashboard that you can basically install
基本上可以安装的仪表板
as a plugin so guess most of you noticed
作为插件，所以猜猜大多数人都注意到了
this is Qabbani oh and i installed it as
这是Qabbani哦，我安装为
a plugin into my elastic search trees
我的弹性搜索树中的插件
distribution and what this does is it
分布及其作用是什么
gives me a general overview about my
给我关于我的一般概述
clusters so i can basically see here
集群，所以我基本上可以在这里看到
that it's a cluster of one which is
这是一个集群的
normally not a good thing because even
通常不是一件好事，因为即使
shows that it's all the stuff is read
显示所有内容都已读取
here because there are no replicas
这里是因为没有副本
assigned so if if the node dies all my
分配的，如果节点死了
search is gone I also get some some
搜索消失了，我也得到了一些
information about CPU usage and all that
有关CPU使用率以及所有其他信息
stuff make it a little bit bigger for
东西使它变得更大
you and oh yeah there's I don't know
你和哦，是的，我不知道
that one that would be the automatic
那将是自动的
comic character mobile node name I have
我有的漫画人物移动节点名称
for this machine but what the model
对于这台机器，但是什么型号
plugin also comes with is this really
插件还附带了这真的吗
nice and handy tool that's called Marvel
好用的工具Marvel
sense it it's a JavaScript page that
感觉这是一个JavaScript页面
offers you Auto completion based on the
为您提供基于
elastic search API so you can basically
弹性搜寻API，因此您基本上可以
get index information from in there and
从那里获取索引信息，然后
you have Auto completion on port
您在端口上具有自动完成功能
it detects the indexes you have in there
它检测到您那里的索引
and office it helps you writing your
和办公室，它可以帮助您编写您的
queries and trying out elasticsearch and
查询并尝试elasticsearch和
playing around you can also use it to do
玩耍也可以用它来做
some analytics and what-have-you
一些分析和你有什么
so it's really really nice a nice plugin
所以它真的非常不错一个不错的插件
it's it's free for development mode you
这是免费的开发模式
have to pay if you if you want to use it
如果您要使用它，必须付费
in production or somewhat but yeah so
在生产或有点，但是的
much on that so what I actually did is I
在那上面很多，所以我实际上是在做
pre-loaded elasticsearch just
预加载的elasticsearch只是
reinitialize that
重新初始化
I preloaded the elastic search index
我预装了弹性搜索索引
which is currently the s - GX index with
当前是s-GX索引
some sessions from the data and
数据中的一些会话和
integration track so basically I added
集成轨迹，所以基本上我添加了
the detox Thomas and and all he gave
排毒托马斯和他给的一切
right after breakfast - the what's new
早餐后就来-最新消息
in spring data talk at a 32d track data
在 spring data 中谈谈32d轨迹数据
integration and what you see already see
整合以及您所看到的已经看到的
here is that I that it takes a JSON
这是我需要一个JSON
document so that's a really nice a nice
文档，这真是太好了
thing about isaac search they can use
他们可以使用以撒搜索的问题
JSON documents to push into the index
JSON文档推入索引
and what elasticsearch then does it it
然后是什么elasticsearch呢
analyzes the data I pushed and tries to
分析我推送的数据并尝试
figure out the schema so basically it
从根本上弄清楚架构
analyzes the data I give it and detect
分析我提供的数据并检测
auto detect more or less or that the
自动检测或多或少或
title will be or might be a string field
标题将是或可能是字符串字段
it will also see a there is a field
它也会看到一个字段
called date that potentially or more
称为潜在或更多日期
sure will be a date having a time and
当然会是一个有时间的日期，
the track might be a string can be
轨道可能是字符串
something I'm but it will be string and
我的东西，但它将是字符串和
what elasticsearch then does is it
elasticsearch然后做的是
creates a schema for you and this is
为您创建一个架构，这是
important because all those search
重要，因为所有这些搜索
server implementations based on Lucene
基于Lucene的服务器实现
require you to have a schema though
需要你有一个模式
they're most of them I mean
他们是他们中的大多数
elasticsearch claims to be more or less
elasticsearch声称或多或少
schema-less so does solar as well but
少方案，太阳能也是如此，但是
there is always a schemer behind
后面总有一个策划者
behind that stuff so there is a schema
在这些东西后面，所以有一个模式
in the search server itself and you can
在搜索服务器本身中，您可以
have a look at this kima and as we
看看这个kima，我们
expected there's basically mappings and
期望基本上有映射和
the within the sessions there are
在会议中有
properties and as you can see there is a
属性，如您所见，有一个
date of type day date so elasticsearch
日期类型日期日期所以弹性搜索
recognized it as a date with an with a
将其识别为带有和的日期
explicit pattern so there the time is
明确的模式，所以时间到了
optional in this case it recognized the
在这种情况下，它可以识别
title as a string and the track as well
标题为字符串，轨道也为
as a string this is really nice and cool
作为一个字符串，这真的很好，很酷
if you if you're working with that but
如果您正在与之合作，但
as you can imagine and since there is is
如你所想，因为有
a dedicated schema in there I could just
我可以在那里有一个专用的架构
go on and try to do that one a raw
继续尝试做一个原始
document and put some invalid field in
文档并将一些无效字段放入
there because someone okay to someone's
在那里，因为有人对某人的同意
mind came into the day it can look like
头脑进入了一天，它看起来像
this and when I try and now try to add
这个，当我尝试现在尝试添加时
it it basically returns me an error
它基本上会返回一个错误
telling me that I cannot add this
告诉我我不能添加这个
document to my index because the types
文档到我的索引，因为类型
don't match so in this case it's very
不匹配，所以在这种情况下
obvious that it won't work but assume
显然，它不会起作用，但是假设
you get numbers in there and the first
你那里有数字，第一个
time you pass in a document it might be
当您传递文件时，可能是
an integer value and the this works fine
一个整数值，这工作正常
for a couple of times and then you
几次，然后你
suddenly start passing on Long's so now
突然开始传给龙，所以现在
you get a problem because these key
你有一个问题，因为这些关键
motels it's an integer you passed in the
汽车旅馆，这是您传入的整数
long you get an error and what you have
多久你会得到一个错误以及你所拥有的
to do then is a schema migration so you
然后要做的是架构迁移，因此您
basically have to to reenacts all that
基本上必须重演所有这些
stuff because you you cannot just change
东西，因为你不能改变
field types as we've seen won't let you
我们已经看到过的字段类型不会让您
do that
去做
so you really have to be careful I mean
所以我真的要小心
it's it's pretty easy to push on
这很容易推动
documents but you have to think about
文件，但您必须考虑
what representation the documents will
文件将代表什么
have within your store and especially in
在您的商店内，尤其是在
elasticsearch and leucine
弹性搜索和亮氨酸
I mean MongoDB is a different piece
我的意思是MongoDB是另一回事
MongoDB is completely schema-less among
MongoDB完全没有架构
UTP you could do this though the search
UTP您可以通过搜索来执行此操作
will be limited depending on the type
视类型而定
you you anthem for research but in
你是研究的国歌，但是
MongoDB it's possible it's not based on
MongoDB可能不是基于
the scene it's it's some it's a
现场是一些
different piece okay so that was a real
不同的部分好吧，那是一个真实的
real short look at what a schema is what
真正的简短了解架构是什么
it does what it's used for there's
它所做的是为了
there's a little bit more to in this
还有更多
schema because you can also add
模式，因为您还可以添加
information on how data is treated so if
有关如何处理数据的信息，如果
you store a document you can basically
您可以基本上存储文档
define how the string let's say the
定义字符串，比如说
string of certain fields is treated if
如果某些字段的字符串被视为
it's split or taking as a whole or if
它是分裂的还是整体的
numbers I'll eliminate it if it's lower
数字，我会消除它，如果它较低
cased what-have-you
装箱了你
so elasticsearch applies a couple of
所以elasticsearch应用了
those or by default but to give you a
这些或默认情况下，但给你一个
real impression it's basically to do
真正的印象基本上是要做的
some analyzation on this particular
关于这个特殊的一些分析
string which is spring one - GX 2015 in
弹簧之一的弦-GX 2015 in
washington DC and when i try to analyze
华盛顿特区，当我尝试分析时
that you can see that there is a bunch
你会看到有一堆
of tokens return a token has always an
的令牌返回，令牌始终具有
offset a type which is alphanumeric you
抵消您是字母数字的类型
can see for 2015 it detects that this is
可以看到2015年它检测到这是
a number there is there is no often
数量不多
often it's not alphanumeric so it can be
通常它不是字母数字，所以可以
treated differently
区别对待
oh yeah that's basically it so you know
哦，是的，基本上就是这样，你知道
every token gets a position and did home
每个令牌都得到一个位置并回家
value it has an offset and so on and so
值具有偏移量，依此类推等等
forth oops
哎呀
so there is a bunch of different
所以有很多不同
different tokenizer
不同的标记器
so I could just consider I could just
所以我可以认为我可以
remove the numeric part by using a
使用a删除数字部分
different tokenizer so if I'm not
不同的分词器，所以如果我不是
interested in my search in any numeric
对我的搜索感兴趣的任何数字
value for whatever reason I could just
无论出于什么原因我都可以珍惜
go on and use a letter tokenizer which
继续使用字母标记器
body
身体
Walt removes the 2015 from the string in
Walt从字符串中删除了2015
there and even the d2 from the 2g ex
甚至还有2g ex的d2
parte token okay
单方令牌好
there's that's to the GDG organizers
这就是GDG组织者
additional to the token Isis I can apply
我可以申请的代币Isis之外
filters to the tokens extracted by the
过滤器提取的令牌
tokenizer so what does that mean
令牌生成器，那是什么意思
basically if you don't define any
基本上，如果您没有定义任何
filters oh the you would have to have
过滤器哦，你将不得不
exact matches basically for spring 1 it
完全匹配，春季1
would be half with capital s and capital
将用大写的s和大写的一半
o but for search that's not always the
o但是对于搜索而言，并不总是
best thing to do so you basically want
最好的做法是让您基本上想要
to do a lower lower it within your
做一个更低的它
within your search index to a take less
在您的搜索索引中花费更少
place and be to be easier searchable
放置并易于搜索
because the user doesn't have to care
因为用户不必关心
about the the original value and camel
关于原始价值和骆驼
casing and what have you and what I
肠衣，你和我有什么
could do as well is I could filter to
可以做的就是我可以过滤到
placate so if I have spring 1 to GX
如果我有春天1到GX
Washington DC in Washington well I could
我可以在华盛顿特区的华盛顿特区
when I now go on in lower case and
当我现在继续小写
unique that you will see that Washington
独特的，你会看到华盛顿
now only shows up at its first when its
现在只在它的第一个出现时
first encountered so as always there is
第一次遇到所以一如既往
there's a little pitfall because the
有一个陷阱，因为
order of filters metals quite a lot so
过滤金属的数量很多
when I mess it up and put a unique
当我把它弄乱并放置一个独特的
filter before the lower case filter it
在小写过滤器之前过滤
won't be able to eliminate the D terms
将无法消除D项
but still lower case them all so what
但是它们还是小写的
happens if I do it that way you can see
如果我这样做的话，你会看到
there's Washington at position 4 and at
华盛顿在第4位，
position 7 through both lower case and
通过小写字母和
that doesn't make too much sense so you
那没有太大意义，所以你
have to be aware of that
必须意识到
when you're dealing with schemers or try
当您与计划者打交道或尝试
to do
去做
to add filters to the implementation so
为实现添加过滤器
the the order really matters and will
顺序真的很重要，并且会
and that's not one I wanted to have
那不是我想要的
thank you okay good so let's let's do it
谢谢，好吧，好吧，让我们开始吧
basic search Oh real quick one find all
基本搜索哦，真正的快速找到所有
documents don't care about anything just
文件根本不在乎什么
to tell you a little bit about scoring
告诉你一些得分
so what I did now is I executed a search
所以我现在要做的是执行搜索
that gave me all documents within my
这给了我所有的文件
index which is basically these sessions
基本上就是这些会话的索引
out there and what I wanted to tell to
在那里，我想告诉
show you is that elasticsearch returns
表明你是Elasticsearch回报
you the number of total hits so you you
您的总点击数，所以您
automatically know how many documents
自动知道多少文件
are in there with you which is a perfect
和你在一起在那里是完美的
match for spring data or page
匹配 spring data 或页面
abstraction because we always tell you
抽象，因为我们总是告诉你
how many how many documents matched your
有多少文件符合您的条件
search it tells you the maximum score
搜索它会告诉您最高分
that was encountered and all all the
遇到的所有
documents that match your search and
符合您搜索条件的文档和
there is this one field which is the
有一个领域是
this core field so score basically tells
这个核心领域，所以分数基本上可以说明
you the relevance of a particular
您与特定内容的相关性
document related to the search terms you
与您搜索字词相关的文档
entered I didn't enter any search term
输入了我没有输入任何搜索词
so it's all documents are equally
所以所有文件都一样
relevant with a hundred percent cuz I
与百分之一百相关
always wanted them so as you can see
一直想要他们，如您所见
there's score there and score there one
那里有分数，那里有一个分数
side note elasticsearch always returns
注意事项elasticsearch总是返回
you the original data structure the
您原始的数据结构
original JSON structure within the
内的原始JSON结构
source element of the Chasen return okay
Chasen的源元素可以返回
now let's have a look at let's say
现在让我们来看看
another search and as you can see I
另一个搜索，如你所见，我
provide I looked for all I did a full
提供我寻找的全部
text search and data so it basically
文本搜索和数据，因此基本上
returns me all the documents that I have
退还我所有的文件
data in in it and those are now ordered
里面的数据，现在已经排序了
by this chorong by relevance this is the
通过相关性，这就是
default behavior of solar and
太阳能和
elasticsearch MongoDB is in this case a
elasticsearch MongoDB在这种情况下是
different piece as well because
也不同，因为
it won't it will use a natural order
它不会使用自然顺序
while elasticsearch and Sola always
而Elasticsearch和Sola总是
return you a squirt order if you don't
如果您不退还给您喷水命令
define it differently so the most
定义不同，所以最
relevant document will be always be
相关文件将永远是
first hit and yeah relevance is
首先是，相关性是
calculated by a word position in the
由单词位置
fields and how often it's there and
字段及其出现的频率，以及
there's a really complex algorithm how
有一个非常复杂的算法
it's done but you can have influence on
完成了，但是您可以对
score so if I basically try to query for
得分，所以如果我基本上尝试查询
multiple fields with a boot and data and
具有引导和数据的多个字段，以及
the title track I you can see this chord
标题轨道，我可以看到此和弦
change because there are multiple search
变化，因为有多个搜索
terms and I restricted it to field and
条款，我将其限制为字段和
peace core values and now look
和平核心价值观，现在看起来
differently and this is something you
不一样，这就是你
very useful because you can get it can
非常有用，因为您可以获得它可以
give your users information in how
向您的用户提供有关如何
potentially relevant the results you
可能与您的结果相关
present them is but you can also
目前他们是，但你也可以
influence his core a little bit so this
影响他的核心有点所以
is something we call boosting because I
之所以称为助推，是因为我
want to have a hit with in the field
希望在该领域获得成功
title to weigh much more than
称号比
potentially within the categories or
可能在类别中或
within the track because I'm not really
在轨道上，因为我不是真的
interested in those I just want to find
对那些我只想找到的人感兴趣
this at the these sessions that have a
这些在这些会议上有一个
boot and data within the title and what
标题中的引导和数据以及什么
I do is here is query time boosting so I
我在这里是查询时间的增加，所以我
tell the search server to treat a search
告诉搜索服务器对待搜索
hit within a certain field differently
在某个领域内命中率不同
so that it weighs more which is
所以它的重量更大
expressed by I don't know the English
我不懂英语表达
word for it it's excellent circumflex
很好的回音
time or times to I don't know power to
我不知道一次或多次的力量
yeah okay basically that that's the
是的，好的，基本上就是
syntax to do sir and if we have a look
先生的语法，如果我们看看
at the currently so currently spring
在目前如此春季
data rest meets hypermedia and security
数据剩余满足超媒体和安全性
is this radiates top let's see if that
这是辐射的顶部，让我们看看是否
no
没有
it still is ready to top but it has a
它仍然准备顶，但它有一个
different weight in there while this
里面有不同的重量
session moved up from below yeah exactly
会话确实从下方向上移动
so the first it didn't change but is
所以第一个没有改变，但是是
because it's the top hit but the second
因为它是最热门但第二
one you see the order changed or
您看到订单已更改，或者
depending on what you defined within
取决于您在其中定义的内容
your query which is kind of nice because
您的查询很好，因为
you can do it when you search actually
您可以在实际搜索时完成
and don't you can also define it prior
而且你也不能事先定义它
within these chemo so you could define
在这些化学中，因此您可以定义
it there so that the user doesn't have
它在那里，以便用户没有
to care but you also can do it at query
照顾，但你也可以在查询
time which is really really nice
时间真的很棒
okay let's move back there's one thing I
好吧，让我们移回去，有一件事我
didn't tell you already about and that's
并没有告诉您有关的信息
the difference between a query and the
查询与
filter query so we heard about scoring
过滤查询，以便我们了解评分
before you should just go on how let me
在你应该继续之前，如何让我
try again
再试一次
hello
你好
oh I crushed the Beamer I'm sorry for
哦，我击碎了Beamer，对此我感到抱歉
that I don't know what just oh it seems
我不知道那是什么
to come back again oh wow okay thumbs up
再次回来哦，哇好吧竖起大拇指
oh yeah okay back I wanted to tell you
哦，好吧，我想告诉你
about query well versus filter query so
关于查询良好与过滤查询的关系
queries basically info have influence on
基本查询信息对
scores so what you search for int well
得分，所以您对int的搜索很好
yeah exactly so fill the queries don't
是的，所以完全可以填充查询
influence score so you basically can
影响力得分，因此您基本上可以
define criteria to eliminate documents
定义消除文件的标准
from your search while without having
从您的搜索而无需
influence on the scoring so the order
对得分的影响，所以顺序
won't still remain will remain as if you
不会仍然存在会像你一样
you hadn't defined it will decree so um
你还没有定义，它将令法令如此
it's yes thank you
是的，谢谢
exactly so let's jump right into it with
正是这样，让我们​​直接进入
MongoDB and see what capabilities we
MongoDB，看看我们有什么功能
have in there how we can build a search
那里有我们如何建立搜索
index and how to use the MongoDB
索引以及如何使用MongoDB
full-text search in there so for this
在那里进行全文搜索
sample I'd like to show you something
样品我想给你看些东西
that's basically I hope you all know the
基本上，我希望大家都知道
site this is our very own website with
网站，这是我们自己的网站，
our block and what we have here is we
我们的街区，这里有我们
integrated full-text search in there
在那里集成了全文本搜索
that's actually backed by elasticsearch
这实际上是由Elasticsearch支持的
behind the scenes and what I want to do
幕后以及我想做什么
is I want to search for a specific
我想搜索一个特定的
Gosling a specific search term and I as
高斯林一个特定的搜索词，我作为
expected I find the latest spring data
希望我能找到最新的 spring data
release train and all that stuff what I
释放火车和所有这些东西
wanted to show you is basically that
想告诉你基本上是
stuff around here which is something
这附近的东西
called facets so facets are are the part
所谓的方面，所以方面是一部分
used for guided navigation so it
用于引导式导航
basically
基本上
you that there are documents that have a
您，有些文件有
certain type cause every blog post is
某种类型的原因是每个博客帖子都是
either reply every content in there is
要么回复其中的每个内容
either a blog post or a guide or what
博客文章或指南或其他内容
have you and blogs are categorized in
你和博客归类于
engineering news and events so every
工程新闻和事件，所以每一个
blog post has basically is assigned to
博客帖子基本上已分配给
category and what faceting does it tells
类别以及它说明了什么
you how many documents matching your
您有多少文件符合您的条件
criteria actually show up in one of
标准实际上显示在
those categories so you can basically
这些类别，因此您基本上可以
guide your user to certain categories or
引导您的用户使用某些类别或
like Amazon does it tells you hey there
像亚马逊一样，它告诉你嘿
is 15 hits in fantasy books and to win
是15本奇幻书籍的热门作品并获胜
others and what have you so that the
别人，你有什么，所以
user can basically drill down and get
用户基本上可以向下钻取
more concrete and what he is looking for
更具体，他正在寻找什么
so this is really nice and what we also
所以这真的很好，我们也
have here I hope you be more resolution
在这里，我希望你能有更多的解决方案
allows this is highlighting so my search
允许这突出显示，所以我的搜索
term yeah I guess it's it's really it's
学期是的，我想这是真的
highlighted in some way so in this case
以某种方式突出显示，因此在这种情况下
it's bold and it has a different break
它是大胆的，它有一个不同的休息时间
background color so those are nice
背景颜色，所以这些都很好
features that search can provide you
搜索可以为您提供的功能
with although I must admit those
尽管我必须承认那些
highlighting and faceting capabilities
突出显示和刻面功能
are a part of fully-fledged search
是全面搜索的一部分
service like our elastic search and
像我们的弹性搜索和
solar there are plans for faceting for a
太阳能有计划为
MongoDB as far as I read in their JIRA
据我在他们的JIRA中阅读的MongoDB
but that hasn't been implemented so far
但是到目前为止还没有实现
but for the major stuff so if you don't
但是对于主要的东西，如果你不这样做
depend on having guided navigation by a
取决于由
facets or a highlighting and that stuff
方面或突出显示内容
MongoDB can do a pretty good job and so
MongoDB可以做的很好，所以
let's build let's build a blog post
让我们建立让我们建立博客
system having full-text search
具有全文搜索的系统
let me just fire up MongoDB
让我启动MongoDB
and use tests so what do we first need
并使用测试，所以我们首先需要什么
to to define is is it can you guys read
要定义的是你们能读吗
that from from the back is it okay or
从背面可以吗？
let me just move it yeah won't go back
让我移动一下，是的，不会回头
okay let's move it up a little bit so I
好吧，让我们将其向上移动一点，以便我
hope that's better what you first need
希望更好的是你首先需要的
to do is we have to define a special
要做的是我们必须定义一个特殊的
index in MongoDB and we can do so by by
MongoDB中的索引，我们可以通过
posting by calling and Sewer index
通过电话和下水道索引发布
giving it all the properties I want to
给它我想要的所有属性
have I want to have full text search
我要全文搜索吗
able and to do so I have to add the add
能够做到这一点，我必须添加
the text keyword basically as as type
文本关键字基本上与类型相同
and the part you can see down here it's
您可以在此处看到的部分是
basically influencing the square of a of
基本上影响a的平方
a document when when it's searched so as
搜索文档时，例如
in the example before I want you to
在这个例子中，我要你
weigh a search it in in title way more
以标题方式衡量搜索结果更多
than one in content and this is
比一个内容，这是
basically the way you have to the only
基本上是您唯一的方式
way at the moment you can influence
目前可以影响的方式
querying with MongoDB so this is indexed
用MongoDB查询，以便对此进行索引
I'm boosting and you have to think about
我正在进步，你必须考虑
it before you actually create your index
在实际创建索引之前
of course it's pretty easy MongoDB to
当然，MongoDB相当容易
just drop the index and recreate it gets
只需删除索引并重新创建它即可
done for you but you have to think about
为您完成，但您必须考虑
it otherwise your search results might
否则您的搜索结果可能
be potentially a little bit lousy okay
可能有点糟糕
so let's let's add this index in there
所以让我们在其中添加该索引
and then just insert some random JSON
然后只插入一些随机的JSON
document as you see I have the detail in
您所看到的文档中有详细信息
here and the content and I just add it
在这里和内容，我只添加它
and then I go on and use MongoDB syntax
然后我继续使用MongoDB语法
for text search which is basically I
用于文本搜索，基本上是我
added agree with dollar text in the
添加了与美元文本一致的
hating I want to do a full text search
讨厌我要全文搜索
and then I give you the search term
然后我给你搜索词
indicated by dollar search and the
由美元搜索和
search for any document that has in
搜索包含以下内容的任何文档
title content or category D string in
标题内容或类别D字符串
and I want to pretty print it and yeah
我想漂亮地打印它，是的
well that doesn't return any results so
好吧，这不会返回任何结果，所以
why is this this is because MongoDB
这是为什么，因为MongoDB
comes with built in stammers tokenizer
内置了stammers令牌生成器
stop words what have you for 16 or so
停止说话你16岁左右
languages I hope I didn't say something
我希望我不会说什么语言
wrong in the here but it should be 16
在这里错了，但应该是16
languages and what those tokenizer send
语言以及令牌生成器发送的内容
stammers do for you is basically in
雄蕊为您做的基本上在
order to keep the search index small and
为了使搜索索引较小并
fast they eliminate common words and in
他们很快消除了常用词，
is it's a very very common phrase
这是一个非常非常普遍的短语吗
so basically when MongoDB sees the
所以基本上当MongoDB看到
document up here it recognizes hey this
记录在这里，它可以识别
is a stop word forget about it I don't
是个停用词，算了我不
need it and so you won't be able to
需要它，所以您将无法
search for it that's something you
搜索它就是你
should be aware of when you're using
应该知道您何时使用
MongoDB so your search terms should the
MongoDB，因此您的搜索词应该
thing you should you want to search for
您应该搜索的东西
it should be in some some shape to this
它应该在某种程度上
mobile DB is okay with because you are
移动数据库还可以，因为您
not able to customize how it behaves
无法自定义其行为
because it's it's just built in there
因为它只是内置在里面
and ready for you to use but you can't
准备好供您使用，但您不能
change it but it worked pretty well if I
更改它，但如果我能很好地工作
just go on and search for let's say
继续搜索就可以说
Washington then okay you see the content
华盛顿然后好吧，您看到的内容
were in Washington was basically the
在华盛顿基本上是
term was contained in the content field
术语包含在内容字段中
and just returned it to me and
刚把它还给我
everything was fine okay so let's just
一切都很好，所以让我们
drop the index again and let's see how
再次删除索引，让我们看看如何
we can do this with spring data okay
我们可以用 spring data 做到这一点
using spring data we have basically the
使用 spring data ，我们基本上有
very same structure we have a blog post
结构非常相似，我们有一篇博客文章
that has a year title the content may be
具有年份标题的内容可能是
assigned to a category and what you see
分配给类别和您所看到的
here is basically this core because I
这基本上是这个核心，因为我
I'm interested in the score I'm
我对自己的分数感兴趣
interested in how good my search results
对我的搜索结果如何感兴趣
are so I added this core field in here
所以我在这里添加了这个核心领域
to pick up the value and what about this
拿起价值，这又如何
little friend here does it tells spring
这里的小朋友告诉春天
data to ignore the property for writing
忽略要写入的属性的数据
a question oh sure yeah sorry okay this
一个问题哦，确定是的，对不起，好的
little friend tells the spring data
小朋友告诉春天的数据
abstraction to just ignore it for
抽象只是忽略它
writing but if it's there or in a result
写作，但如果在那里或结果
it just reads the value back into your
它只是将值读回到您的
your domain type okay let's go on and do
您的域名类型好吧，让我们继续
some simple search so as you saw before
一些简单的搜索，如您之前所见
we can create the index manually on the
我们可以在
console and we spring data you basically
控制台，我们基本上会为您提供数据
have something called a text index
有一些叫做文本索引的东西
definition with the Builder so we
定义与建设者，所以我们
basically define a on on the field title
基本上在字段标题上定义一个
I want to have a weight of three on the
我想把三重
content field to the default is 140
内容字段默认为140
categories field then I create the index
类别字段，然后创建索引
definition and tell the index operations
定义并告诉索引操作
for it the blog post type to just create
为此，只需创建博客文章类型
the index for me pretty simple and then
对我来说索引很简单，然后
I can go on and whoops just define a
我可以继续说，只要定义一个
text criteria for default language which
默认语言的文本标准
is a MongoDB basically English but I can
是一个MongoDB，基本上是英语，但是我可以
use any of the other sixteen one
使用其他十六个之一
matching any search term my hands in
匹配我手上的任何搜索词
here which may be release because I I
在这里可能被释放，因为
just downloaded a sample of the of our
刚刚下载了我们的
blog to show up in here to have a
博客出现在这里有一个
concise result and then basically
简洁的结果，然后基本上
execute that stuff using the Mongo
使用Mongo执行这些东西
operations call find within with the
操作调用中找到
criteria I can basically chain other
我基本上可以连锁其他的标准
criterias to the text search one as long
文字搜索的标准只要一个
as I don't use a special index such as a
因为我不使用特殊索引，例如
geospatial search I can use other terms
地理空间搜索我可以使用其他术语
to combine it so I could basically also
结合起来，所以我基本上也可以
say and the the document must have
说，文件必须有
category release what have
分类发布有什么
you okay and that basically execute the
你还好，基本上执行
search for me and when you see it down
寻找我，当你看到它
here is the result and notable is that
这是结果，值得注意的是
this core field though I have it here
这个核心领域虽然我在这里
within my domain type is currently null
我的域内的类型当前为null
this is because MongoDB doesn't doesn't
这是因为MongoDB不会
by default return you this core field
默认情况下，返回此核心字段
because it takes some time and blows up
因为要花一些时间然后炸毁
the result size and what have you so you
结果的大小，你有什么所以你
have to explicitly tell MongoDB to give
必须明确告诉MongoDB给
it to you and you can do this by
它给你，你可以做到这一点
defining a text query given this very
鉴于此，定义了一个文本查询
same criteria we have before and
我们之前拥有的相同标准和
beautify you have to define the field of
美化您必须定义
this core of this core field and then
这个核心领域的核心，然后
you can basically also sort by this
您基本上也可以按此排序
field otherwise you wouldn't be able to
字段，否则您将无法
sort via this core
通过此核心排序
MongoDB returns natural order as you can
MongoDB尽可能返回自然顺序
see down here this is just just iOS or
看看这里，这只是iOS或
the the way there there within this door
在这扇门里面的路
and then you can basically go on and use
然后您基本上可以继续使用
this query tool to order your results
使用此查询工具对结果进行排序
and when I do that let me just execute
当我这样做时，我就执行
it you can see that this core field is
你可以看到这个核心领域是
now there for you so your interest it
现在在那里给你，所以你的兴趣
got returned to you as well as that the
得到了你的回馈
order of the results is different
结果的顺序不同
because we now order by score but that
因为我们现在按分数排序，但是
wouldn't be spring data if we weren't
如果不是，那将不是 spring data
there to try to make it as easy for you
在那里尝试使它变得容易
to use this technology as as we can so
尽我们所能使用这项技术
what we provide you additionally with is
我们还为您提供的是
something called the text score
所谓的文字比分
annotation which is basically which has
注释基本上是
the read-only annotation as its meta
只读注释作为其元数据
annotation so it's basically read-only
注解，因此基本上是只读的
field but when we detect a property that
字段，但是当我们检测到一个属性时，
has this annotation within your domain
在您的域内有此注释
type and you're using MongoDB we assume
类型，而您使用的是MongoDB，我们假设
that you're interested in this core so
您对这个核心感兴趣
we add all that additional part to the
我们将所有其他部分添加到
query that you otherwise would have to
查询您否则必须
type
类型
and so that is the this core always gets
所以这就是核心
returned to you and what we also have is
回到你身边，我们还有
we have the automatic index creation for
我们有自动创建索引
you ready so you can basically add the
您已经准备好，因此您基本上可以添加
text index annotation in there give it a
那里的文本索引注释给它一个
weight like we we did there before let
像我们在那之前做的那样重
me just copy that
我只要复制那个
let's call this two and that one has no
我们称这两个为无
weight just default is just one but it
重量只是默认值之一，但它
should be indexed so this is pretty much
应该被索引，所以这差不多
all you need to do to get rid of what I
您需要做的所有事情来摆脱我的
showed you here about this little stuff
向您展示了这些小东西
and what I can now do is basically I
我现在所能做的基本上是
have my my aunty my domain type defined
定义我的阿姨域类型
I edit those annotations and it can do
我编辑这些注释，它可以做到
basically the same search just using
基本上只使用相同的搜索
repository abstraction without having to
无需抽象存储库
interact with any of the of the
与的任何互动
templating stuff or the lower level API
模板或较低级别的API
so it's pretty pretty easy all you have
所以你拥有的一切都非常容易
to do is to pass in a text criteria or
要做的就是传递文字标准或
use the text criteria as part of some
使用文本标准作为某些内容的一部分
other criteria will detect that and then
其他条件将检测到，然后
just execute the full text search query
只需执行全文搜索查询
that's pretty easy yeah you can also
这很简单，是的，你也可以
combine it with non matching and
结合不匹配和
what-have-you or all the stuff that
你有什么或所有的东西
MongoDB basically offers you okay time
MongoDB基本上为您提供了良好的时间
moves on I have to hurry up a little bit
继续前进，我必须快一点
great so I think we're basically done
太好了，我想我们已经基本完成了
with the MongoDB abstraction I'll show
我将展示MongoDB抽象
you that there are stammers and stop
你有结巴并停下来
words that this core isn't return that
这个核心没有回报的话
you have to explicitly have it to sort
您必须明确地对其进行排序
we did the index creation and the
我们做了索引创建和
automatic index creation with the decree
使用该命令自动创建索引
ring and this Corinne yes thank you
响了，这个Corinne是的，谢谢
oh yeah there's there's one thing I
哦，是的，我有一件事
wanted to mention as well you also can
也想提一提
make use of these Corinne within the
在内部使用这些Corinne
derived queries so you can basically use
派生查询，因此您基本上可以使用
the
的
natural spring data or the bylaws within
天然弹簧数据或其中的细则
your method declaration and it will just
您的方法声明，它将只是
work as you expect it to do so this is
如您所愿地工作，这是
pretty pretty neat
整齐漂亮
exactly okay
完全可以
Oh questions so far - MongoDB otherwise
到目前为止的问题-否则MongoDB
I'll move on - yeah question
我继续-是的问题
ah
啊
oh I don't actually know because it's
哦，我实际上不知道，因为
one of the community modules I can check
我可以检查的社区模块之一
with later on we can we can have a check
以后我们可以检查一下
I'm sorry I don't actually know that
对不起，我实际上并不知道
okay so moving on to - spring data solar
好吧，现在继续-Spring Data Solar
and as I said before there is no Lucene
就像我之前说的，没有Lucene
based search server that's really
基于搜索的服务器
schema-less so what you have in solar as
无需架构，因此您在太阳能领域所拥有的
well is something called schema and
好是所谓的架构，
apparently it's an XML document within
显然，这是一个XML文档
that XML document you have something you
该XML文档中您有一些东西
have the key fields defined so basically
基本上定义了关键字段
there is an IDE that's of type string
有一个类型为字符串的IDE
and now comes the interesting part it's
现在有趣的部分是
indexed you have to set the the index
建立索引必须设置索引
value to true in order to have it
值为true才能拥有它
searchable if it's false you won't be
可搜索，如果它是假的，你不会
able to query for it it would give you
能够查询它会给你
an error that there is there's no such
没有这样的错误
feeling doesn't know anything about it
感觉一无所知
then that's all and the next next prop
那就是全部，下一个道具
attribute is stored so what the stored
属性被存储，所以存储了什么
means Stewart means this property is
表示Stewart表示此属性是
there to be returned to you as part of
在那里作为您的一部分退还给您
your search result within the document
您在文档中的搜索结果
okay it's required and multivalued
好吧，这是必需的并且是多值的
that's nothing nothing really special
没什么没什么特别的
but if you basically have a field that's
但是如果您基本上有一个字段
not stored it can be potentially used
没有存储它可以潜在地使用
for for searching so you have that you
用于搜索，因此您拥有
have as in elasticsearch special fields
与elasticsearch专业领域一样
fulfilling a dedicated purpose so if you
完成一个专门的目的，所以如果你
have a title field
有一个标题栏
or let's say the name field then you
或者说名称字段，那么您
store the name as it is normally within
按照通常的名称存储名称
your within your index it's typically
通常在您的索引范围内
indexed and Stewart which means it's
索引和斯图尔特，这意味着
part of the result but for searching you
结果的一部分，但用于搜索您
want to have a probably a lowercase a
想要一个可能是小写的
lowercase field in there so that the
在那里有小写字母
user doesn't have to worry about case or
用户不必担心大小写或
in these search terms so you have to add
这些搜索字词中，因此您必须添加
an additional field that might be of
可能是
type lowercase which then is not stored
键入小写字母，然后不存储
just who is interested in in the lower
只是谁对低端感兴趣
case result pretty much no one but it's
案件结果几乎没人，但是
useful to have it in there because you
放在里面很有用，因为您
need to query for it okay and here you
需要查询就可以了，在这里你
can basically see a field type
基本上可以看到一个字段类型
definition as we saw before there is
我们之前所看到的定义
this field called name that has the type
此字段的名称为type
text general and behind that field type
常规文本，该字段类型后面
definition there is basically the
定义基本上是
information how the field should be
信息领域应该如何
treated within the search server so
在搜索服务器内处理过
basically it gets tokenized where the
基本上它被标记化
standard tokenizer factory which just
标准令牌生成器工厂
takes two string as it is not applying
需要两个字符串，因为它不适用
any tokenization you could use letter to
您可以使用字母进行的任何标记化
organize and what have you there's there
整理，那里有什么
is a bunch of those listed up at the
是一堆列出的
website i pretty much explained what
网站我几乎解释了什么
they do and then it's a lowercase filter
他们这样做，然后是一个小写过滤器
Factory which just lowers the string for
工厂只是降低了字符串
for indexing so basically all the values
用于索引，因此基本上所有值
are all written lowercase into the index
都以小写形式写入索引
and you also can define a special
您还可以定义一个特殊的
treatment for queries so when a query
处理查询，以便在查询时
comes in the string provided a query
出现在字符串中，提供查询
string is also tokenized
字符串也被标记
and stop words are limited and all that
和停用词是有限的，所有这些
stuff so there's there's really a lot of
东西，所以那里真的有很多
a lot behind the type information that
类型信息背后有很多
gives you so so you got
给你，所以你得到了
points to tweak your index in there and
指向在那里调整索引，
how your search behaves by just
您的搜索行为如何
adjusting the field type definitions but
调整字段类型定义，但
again you have to be careful because or
同样，您必须要小心，因为或
think about what you want to do before
考虑一下你想做什么
you're going to protect you with it
你会用它来保护你
because again if you change stuff in
因为再次，如果你改变东西
there this can probably result in the
那里可能会导致
need to index the stuff and re-indexing
需要索引内容并重新索引
depending on the size of your index can
根据您的索引大小可以
take several hours or days or really
需要几个小时或几天甚至是
really long
真的很长
okay and what solar also has is
好，太阳能也有
something called managed
称为托管
chemo mode which is oh basically more or
基本上是更多的化学模式或
less the same as we have in
与我们所拥有的不一样
elasticsearch so so it takes the first
elasticsearch，所以它需要第一个
document it sees for a collection and
收集到的文档，以及
then tries to somehow guess DD field
然后尝试以某种方式猜测DD字段
types and let me just spin up a solar
打字，让我旋转太阳能
instance for you so I'm using the
实例给你，所以我在用
example that comes with these a lot
这些附带的例子
distribution so there's basically an
分布，所以基本上有一个
example of a cloud this cloud setup
此云设置的云示例
within the distribution that you can use
在您可以使用的发行版中
it's pretty simple to start up and then
启动非常简单，然后
it just allows you to go to the solar
它只是让你去太阳能
admin which looks like this and you can
管理员看起来像这样，你可以
see on the cloud tab that there is
在云标签上看到
basically one index that's called
基本上是一个称为
getting started since it's the it's the
入门，因为它是
example it's Charlotte there are two
例如夏洛特有两个
nodes actually available and what I have
实际可用的节点以及我拥有的
done here is the the index itself and I
在这里完成的是索引本身，而我
can go on and query three in there and
可以继续查询那里的三个
behind all that there is the oops
在所有的东西后面
there is the schema so the schema is
有架构，所以架构是
basically hidden in some file within the
基本上隐藏在
index itself
索引本身
what meaning can I
我有什么意思
it's called managed schema in this case
在这种情况下称为托管模式
and down in there so there's a basic
在里面，所以有一个基本的
configuration in there
那里的配置
you can see that there are already field
您可以看到已经有字段
types contained and there are some they
包含的类型有一些
have there is a name field that has a
有一个名称字段有一个
type of text general and there are
文字类型一般，有
dynamic fields in there so you can
那里的动态字段，因此您可以
basically define wildcards so that every
基本上定义通配符，以便每个
field that ends with underscore I is
以下划线I结尾的字段是
treated as an integer so there there is
视为整数，所以有
a schemer underneath and it's in in that
在下面的策划者
particular file that gets updated so if
更新的特定文件，所以如果
there is a solar sees a new field when
有一个太阳能看到一个新领域，当
you add a document basically there is
您基本上添加了一个文档
the field is added to to this very file
该字段已添加到此文件中
so and when I now want to search solo I
所以当我现在想独自搜寻时
can basically click go on and take the
基本上可以单击继续并采取
the field names in there and search for
那里的字段名称并搜索
two somewhat hot search starting with
两个有点热的搜索开始
all the documents are are returned to me
所有文件都退还给我
that start with a CA n which is
以CA n开头的
basically cannon or yeah there there's a
基本上是大炮或是的，有一个
power shot and what-have-you
强力射击和你有什么
and what I wanted to show you is
我想告诉你的是
basically are highlighting in there as
基本上在那里突出显示为
we saw it in in the blog post example so
我们在博客文章示例中看到了
we saw you have to really know about the
我们看到您必须真正了解
degree string so you have to learn the
度字符串，所以您必须学习
query language and highlighting is is
查询语言，突出显示的是
one of those stuff which is represented
那些代表的东西之一
represented by HL or highlight but you
由HL代表或突出显示，但您
have to know it and then there is FL
必须知道，然后有FL
which is basically the list of fields
这基本上是字段列表
highlighting should be applied to so
突出显示应应用于
it's not that really nice of a usage so
它的用法不是很好，所以
you can basically add a store which is
您基本上可以添加一个商店
apply it on all fields and do the
将其应用于所有字段并执行
highlighting in there
在那里突出
this is a remarkable because here you
这很了不起，因为在这里
see the response with the document and
查看文档的回复，并
those are two documents and down here
那是两个文件，在这里
below next to the actual search result
在实际搜索结果旁边
there is the highlighting result so the
有突出显示的结果，所以
highlighting is is not actually done
突出显示实际上没有完成
within the document you get in return
在您得到的文件中
but next to it that's the same for
但旁边的意思是一样的
elasticsearch so you have to manually
elasticsearch，所以您必须手动
check which IDs down here match one of
检查以下哪些ID与以下其中一项匹配
the documents up there to merge together
那里的文件合并在一起
the string in here because there is that
这里的字符串是因为
Canon is defined and here is in the name
佳能被定义，这里是名称
field it's highlighted so it's not
字段高亮显示，因此不是
automatically included and that is also
自动包含在内
reflected within the spring data solar
反映在 spring data 中
as well as well in the spring data
以及 spring data
elasticsearch abstractions there are
弹性搜索抽象有
highlight pages and faceted faceting
突出显示页面和多面
pages and all that stuff that pretty
页面和所有这些漂亮的东西
much give you access to the highlighting
很多让您可以访问突出显示
as its returned from the store
从商店退回
implementation so we don't do the
实施，所以我们不做
merging for you you still have to do it
为您合并，您仍然必须这样做
manually because we don't want to
手动，因为我们不想
interfere with what is natural to the
干扰自然
store and that's what how they work okay
存储，这就是他们如何工作的
so getting back to the three
所以回到三个
presentation okay we saw the manage
演示好了，我们看到了管理
schema one other thing that I wanted to
计划另一件事，我想
mention is that the for full-text search
提到的是全文搜索
you need something like copy field
您需要类似复制字段的内容
controller which basically you define a
控制器，您基本上可以定义一个
set of fields that you want your values
您想要您的值的一组字段
to be copied into another field
复制到另一个字段
so normally you define an underscore
所以通常你定义一个下划线
textile squirrel what have you feel and
松鼠，你有什么感觉，
then define the rule copy field swore
然后定义规则复制字段
star all the fields that are in the
为所有的字段加星标
document copied them into the
文档将它们复制到
destination text field and then you can
目标文本字段，然后您就可以
go on and query for the underscore text
继续查询下划线文字
what have you and that's the way how
你有什么，这就是方式
text search works
文字搜索作品
there so but what get out sure
在那里，但是什么肯定
let's have a look at a simple solar
让我们看一个简单的太阳能
query you saw it in the API before in
查询您之前在API中看到的内容
Java it looks a little bit different so
Java，看起来有点不同，所以
this is just a random and method find by
这只是一个随机的方法
name or description given the name and
名称或说明的名称和
the description the description and we
说明说明，我们
want to look it up in solar I want to
想在太阳能中查找它，我想
need to do without the spring data
需要没有弹簧数据
abstractions basically go on take the
抽象基本上继续
query string know the name escape or the
查询字符串知道名称转义或
input because there could be wildcards
输入，因为可能有通配符
in there I I don't want to use a to let
我在那里不想用a让
use or reg a regular expressions or what
使用或注册正则表达式或其他
have you I have to concoct it with or
你有我要炮制吗？
again use the S declined utils to escape
再次使用拒绝的S工具逃脱
the stuff then I need to define a solo
然后我需要定义一个独奏
career tell it to set start and rose
事业告诉它开始和上升
this is basically the pagination
这基本上是分页
information to get the number of total
信息获取总数
values so how many documents actually
值，所以实际上有多少文件
match that result and then I execute the
匹配该结果，然后执行
decree again fetching all those results
法令再次获取所有这些结果
to really get a list otherwise the law
真正获得清单，否则法律
would kick in and limit my search to ten
将开始并将我的搜索限制为十个
results or the default that is defined
结果或定义的默认值
within the index so this is a pretty a
在索引中，所以这是一个相当
lot of code I even added an exception
很多代码我甚至添加了一个异常
translator and all that stuff that you
翻译者和您所有的东西
would have to write not using this print
将不得不写不使用此打印
data so what's bringing data in the case
数据，那么案子带来了什么
of solar office use again a query API so
太阳能办公室再次使用查询API，因此
that you don't have to know the syntax
您不必知道语法
of name and the the or clause and all
名称，the或子句以及所有
that stuff or the circumflex for
那个东西或抑扬音
boosting or what-have-you or
提升或拥有你或
highlighting so there's there is a high
突出所以有一个高
level API a fluent API so something we
级别的API流畅的API，所以我们
are pretty used to and we also offer you
非常习惯，我们也为您提供
the derived query mechanism so this
派生的查询机制，所以这
basically boils down to again having
基本上归结为
just that method as within your
就像您内部的那种方法
repository
资料库
interface and that's all you need and
界面，这就是您所需要的，
you're good to go to execute the search
你很好去执行搜索
as long as you
只要你
as long as your index matches what you
只要您的索引与您的匹配
want to do that's always there okay are
想要做的事情总是存在的
we doing time I have to hurry up a
我们在做时间，我必须快点
little bit so I'll I'll skip that one as
一点，所以我会跳过那个
we saw a boosting before you can
我们看到了提振
basically define boosting while the
基本上定义了提升
circumflex oh and in spring that isola
抑扬灵哦，在春天那伊索拉
it's pretty pretty easy to do create
创建起来非常容易
time boosting by just having the add
只需添加即可节省时间
boost annotation on any method parameter
在任何方法参数上增加注释
you want to have and we'll make sure
您想要拥有，我们将确保
that this our annotation this value gets
这个我们的注释这个值得到
picked up is applied to to the actual a
拾取后应用于实际
query executed which is a kind of nice
查询执行，这是一种不错的选择
thing and we also have support for the
事情，我们也对
scoring because again as in MongoDB by
得分是因为再次出现在MongoDB中
default the score is it's not returned
默认分数是不返回
for an individual document so you have
对于单个文档，这样您就可以
in basically in solar if you are
如果你是在太阳能
interested in the score you have to
对分数有兴趣
define the fields that should be
定义应该是的字段
returned as part of the result and let
作为结果的一部分返回并让
me just quickly show you that you
我只是迅速向你表明你
basically would have this is FL field
基本上会有FL场
list you would have to as you can see in
您将必须看到的清单
here here's the the here's the document
这是文档
and it doesn't have a score field there
而且那里没有分数字段
there is none in there so you have to
那里没有东西，所以你必须
define I want to have all the fields and
定义我想拥有所有领域和
I want to have the score field as well
我也想要分数区
and then execute degree and all of a
然后执行度数和所有
sudden the score field is in there so
突然得分场在那里
it's not very useful for that particular
对于那个特定的来说不是很有用
query but if I combine it with some
查询，但如果我结合一些
other criteria the the score would
得分的其他标准
change but the point is what we have for
变化，但重点是我们所拥有的
you is not only that one but also the
你不仅是那个，也是
other annotation as we saw in MongoDB
我们在MongoDB中看到的其他注释
there is text score and as those two
有文字分数和那两个
projects are you all from the different
你们都是来自不同的人
pace there's in this case it's just
在这种情况下，只是
called score they are
他们叫分数
are and there's something in that istick
是的，在那个istick里有东西
searches world and and we're trying to
搜索世界，我们正在努力
move those sometime in the future
在将来的某个时候移动那些
together to have it unified more or less
或多或少地统一起来
so that there is a dedicated matter
所以有一个专门的事情
annotation that indicates hey this is
注释，表示这是
relevant for search and it's it's a
与搜索相关，这是一个
score field so we can do that with the
得分字段，因此我们可以使用
composable annotation model we have in
我们拥有的可组合注释模型
spring as well so but that's that's
春天也是这样，但这就是
something we want to do okay and as you
我们想做的事情与您一样
saw before the D result highlighting is
在D结果突出显示之前看到
you have to know about the HL pairing
您必须了解HL配对
parameter that you have to do in know
您必须知道的参数
how it's done and in with the spring
春天的来临
data abstraction it basically boils down
数据抽象基本上可以归结为
to this very one annotation so you can
这个注释，所以您可以
add add highlights define a
添加添加亮点定义一个
fragmentation size and the number of
碎片大小和数量
snippets so it basically tells you how
片段，因此基本上可以告诉您如何
how many characters from beginning to
从头到尾有多少个字符
end where the the search term is found
在找到搜索词的地方结束
is is returned and how many snippets in
返回，并包含多少个片段
maximum you should be returned there's
最大的你应该返回那里
there is a bunch of other parameters as
还有一堆其他参数
well like let me just
就像让我
yeah there's the highlight and there's
是的，有亮点，有
there's quite a few others as well so
还有很多其他的
there's you can define the fields you
您可以定义字段
can find a format a prefix or postfix if
可以找到格式的前缀或后缀，如果
you don't like the default the default
你不喜欢默认
is p.m. I guess yeah yeah and you can
是下午，我想是的，你可以
define an explicit query so there's
定义一个明确的查询，所以
there's lots of options in within that
里面有很多选择
annotation so it's pretty much
注释，所以差不多
everything this already I office to for
我已经处理过的所有事情
you and quite simple in there okay
你，在那里很简单
okay and the last thing I wanted to show
好的，我想展示的最后一件事
you is about the the schema API so what
您是关于架构API的，那又如何
we learned in the beginning is that
我们在一开始就知道
there is a schemer in there and that's a
那里有一个计划者，那是一个
lot tries to guess what it looks like
很多尝试猜测它看起来像什么
and what we offer you is basically the
我们提供给您的基本上是
at index annotation so that you can give
在索引注释处，以便您可以
hints to researcher about how to treat
向研究人员提示如何治疗
fields and the types in there which is
字段和其中的类型是
kind of handy and prove hopefully
方便，希望能证明
prevents you from running into indexing
阻止您进入索引
in issues so if you want to use this
问题，所以如果你想使用这个
it's there for you it uses the the solar
它在那里为您使用太阳能
for schema API or we recently upgraded
用于模式API或我们最近升级了
master solar 5 which is coming with the
主太阳能5与
next release
下一个版本
but yeah it's there for you to use and
但是，是的，在那里您可以使用和
pretty simple it was just as you
很简单，就像你一样
expected to do its yet index a notation
期望做它尚未索引的符号
can be used as an alternative to source
可以用作来源的替代
very own field annotation which doesn't
自己的字段注释
allow you to define index informations
允许您定义索引信息
in there just tells you which fields -
在那里告诉您哪些字段-
to be indexed but not how with with this
被索引，但不如何与此
one you can do it ok
一个你可以做到的
then let's move on to the final part of
然后我们继续到
this talk which will be a lot about
这个话题将会很重要
elastic search we saw a lot of elastic
弹性搜索，我们看到了很多弹性
search in the beginning so it's
在开始搜索，所以
basically this search server that takes
基本上，这个搜寻伺服器
the JSON documents has this schema
JSON文档具有此架构
detection or it even allows you to have
检测，甚至可以让您拥有
nested documents within your within your
您内部的嵌套文档
structures but that can drastically
结构，但可以大大
decrease performance if you use it so be
如果使用它会降低性能
careful with that
小心一点
especially when when doing queries and
特别是在进行查询和
what I wanted to show you an elastic
我想给你展示一种弹性
search is basically the indexing stuff
搜索基本上是索引的东西
so you have the add document annotation
所以你有添加文档注释
that lets you basically define where
基本上可以定义
your domain type should be put so it is
您的域名类型应该这样
possible to have index define where the
可能有索引定义
add index name which is the route type
添加索引名称，即路由类型
and then you can store different types
然后您可以存储不同的类型
different types of documents within that
其中不同类型的文件
collection so this this book is
收藏，所以这本书是
basically stored in the pub
基本上存放在酒吧
collection and is of type book obviously
集合，显然是类型的书
so if I translate this to request to
所以如果我翻译这个请求
elasticsearch it basically is a put on
elasticsearch基本上是一个穿上
the index of publication with type dog
狗类型的出版指数
and some ID what have you and the values
和一些ID你有什么价值
as priority JSON document
作为优先JSON文档
well I now can also do is have a class
我现在也可以做的是上一堂课
article which is also stored in the
文章也存储在
collection of publications but it's of
出版物的集合，但它的
type articles so this schema up there
输入文章，以便该模式在那里
would change to publications article
将更改为出版物文章
what have you ID the thing you have to
你有什么身份证件
be aware of is that the properties of
要知道的是
both those types need to match so if you
这两种类型都需要匹配，所以如果您
have let's say a name in the book type
让我们在书本类型中说一个名字
which is a string and you have name in
这是一个字符串，您在
article which is a name type while you
您使用的是名字类型的文章
type what have you then that's not
输入你有什么，那不是
allowed this will give you an indexing
允许这样做将为您建立索引
error so those those have to match if
错误，所以那些必须匹配，如果
you have a name in one you have to the
你有一个名字，你必须
same type to have the same in the other
同一类型在另一个中具有相同的
oh okay
哦好的
and let's bring that elasticsearch also
并让我们也进行弹性搜索
offers you same as we've solar some kind
为您提供与我们一样的太阳能服务
of API to influence the structure of
API影响结构
your schema so in elastic search it's
您的架构，因此在弹性搜索中
done via the add field annotation that
通过添加字段注释完成
lets you define or basically lets you
让您定义或基本上让您
define the type of the field so you can
定义字段的类型，以便您可以
have basically a string that is a date
基本上有一个字符串是一个日期
and tell elasticsearch to apply to that
并告诉elasticsearch适用于
specific string to treat it as a date
将其视为日期的特定字符串
with a specific format or you can use
使用特定格式，或者您可以使用
geolocation data in there which is
那里的地理位置数据
translated to a long laptop and what
翻译成一台很长的笔记本电脑，什么
have you interesting is the multi field
你有趣的是多领域
or annotation because that one basically
或注释，因为基本上
creates the you can assign different
创建您可以分配不同的
analyzers and indexes as we learn today
我们今天学习的分析器和索引
to a specific field to it basically
到特定领域
in that case it would be an author's
在这种情况下，那将是作者的
field and there would be a dedicated
领域，将有一个专门的
field that's used for surging using a
用于使用
keyword analyzer so a different analyzer
关键字分析器，所以与众不同
than the actual one and so it would
比实际的，所以它会
there would be an additional field
会有一个额外的领域
authors dot sort using the keyword
作者使用关键字进行点排序
analyzer so this is pretty neat because
分析仪，所以这很整洁，因为
it helps you set up your your domain
它可以帮助您设置您的域
type to be really really searchable for
可以真正真正搜索到的类型
the use cases you have well so there's
您的用例很好，所以有
there's of course I curate a dedicated
我当然会策划一个专门的
query API that you can use there's the
您可以使用的查询API
very own spring data criteria API for
自己的spring数据标准API
pretty simple queries so you basically
非常简单的查询，因此您基本上
define where location and use some some
定义位置并使用一些
GU point and then you're good to go
顾点，然后你就好了
of course there's elastic search has has
当然有弹性搜索
many more capabilities than just doing
功能远远不止
search by it by some properties so you
通过一些属性进行搜索，这样您
can basically go on and use the native
基本上可以继续使用本机
search query builder it's calling the
搜索查询构建器正在调用
end up project to you and then apply
结束项目，然后申请
filters to it so you can you can define
对其进行过滤，以便您可以定义
a boolean filter with exactly the same
具有完全相同的布尔过滤器
terminology as you have within elastic
弹性内的术语
search in the web UI as you saw when you
如您所见，在网络用户界面中进行搜索
construct the command so it's a boolean
构造命令，所以它是一个布尔值
filter with a must and then the D terms
先过滤，然后过滤D项
must match spring and what-have-you so
必须与春天和你相匹配
you have access to all the elastic
您可以使用所有的弹性
search capabilities where the native
搜索功能原生
search query below okay so let me just
搜索下面的查询好吧，让我就
show you some elastic search I wanted to
给你看一些我想要的弹性搜索
show with elastic search I wanted to
用弹性搜索显示
basically show you a setting so this is
基本上给你看一个设置，所以这是
a useful guide in navigation and as I
导航方面的有用指南
said before there is a the facet
说之前有一个方面
abstraction in there so as a result of a
在那里的抽象
facet enquiry you get a facet patient
方面查询，您有一个方面的患者
return which for which you can basically
基本上可以返回
get out the terms so in this example
弄清楚条款，在这个例子中
there is a list of
有一个清单
Frances in years the ante conferences
几年前的法兰西斯会议
are about a bunch of terms like Springs
关于像Springs这样的术语
collar elasticsearch people on a cloud
领elasticsearch人在云上
and what-have-you
还有你
so this is the content of the conference
这就是会议的内容
and we want to know for all the
我们想知道所有
documents within that collection
该馆藏中的文件
basically how often does the term
基本上这个词多久一次
Java or what-have-you a cure and when I
Java或您有什么治愈方法以及何时
execute that it's a regular spring boot
执行这是一个常规的弹簧靴
episode all of those to our
将所有这些都播放给我们
implementation basically have spring
实现基本上有春天
boot auto-configuration for you ready
引导自动配置为您准备好
and when I execute to create you can
当我执行创建时，您可以
basically see oh my my query for all the
基本上看到了我所有的查询
documents there there are four
文件那里有四个
conferences that much about two for
会议大约两个
spring one for Scala play keep on our
Scala播放的春季第一曲继续
elasticsearch what have you so this is
elasticsearch你怎么了，这是
pretty nice for for the bodyguardian
对于保镖来说非常好
navigation and pretty handy since
导航和很方便
elasticsearch recently well it didn't
elasticsearch最近很好，但是没有
actually remove facets but it deprecated
实际上删除了构面，但已弃用
facets in in favor of aggregations there
有利于聚合的方面
is a support for that as well so
也为此提供了支持
aggregations are our the next step of
聚合是我们的下一步
facet so to speak they are facets on
可以这么说，
steroids so you can do much more there's
类固醇，所以您可以做更多的事情
a dedicated documentation on the
有关的专用文档
elasticsearch site but just to show you
elasticsearch网站，但只是为了向您展示
the very same query in another in
在另一个相同的查询
another way using the aggregation is
使用聚合的另一种方法是
basically I have a search query the same
基本上我有一个相同的搜索查询
as before for a search type and then I
和以前一样搜索类型，然后我
edit aggregation for terms below that's
编辑以下术语的汇总
basically just the same as we saw up
基本上和我们看到的一样
here just that it's formatted a little
这里只是格式化了一点
differently and that I don't use a facet
不同的是，我不使用刻面
with a facet or request builder but I
与构面或请求构建器有关，但我
use the aggregations and this basically
使用聚合，这基本上
just gives me the the same output as
只是给我相同的输出
before so there's there's support for
在此之前，有对
both the old and the new versions of
新旧版本的
faceting okay great
刻面还可以
yes oh facets we saw aggregations this
是的，我们在各个方面都看到了汇总
brings me more or less
带给我或多或少
hey we got a few minutes left to to the
嘿，我们还有几分钟的时间
end all of the code you saw today is
结束您今天看到的所有代码是
available on github oh you can check it
在github上可用哦，您可以检查一下
out play around with it there's our very
玩一下它，这是我们非常
own spring data examples or git
自己的spring数据示例或git
repository there is all the examples we
仓库中有我们所有的例子
have in there for Cassandra
在那里有卡桑德拉
elasticsearch GPA so all the other storm
elasticsearch GPA，其他所有风暴
would use modules as well
也会使用模块
everything I showed you today is there
我今天给你看的一切都在那里
up there you can check it out as well as
在那里你也可以检查出来
the others sometimes we're already
其他人有时候我们已经
crafting new new features within the
在
examples so you may want to check out
例子，所以你可能想看看
some of the development branches of
一些发展分支
those as well to see what we're up to
那些也看看我们在做什么
for the next release but yeah if you've
对于下一个版本，但如果您已经
got any questions feel free to ask or
有任何问题随时问或
come to the birds of a feather
来到羽毛的鸟儿
I guess it's tomorrow or or come come by
我想是明天还是来了
later I'm here for the rest of the
后来我在这里休息
conference if there are no questions oh
发布会如果没有问题哦
I wish you a very nice rest of the
祝您休息愉快
conference and show it and goodbye
会议并展示并告别
thank you
谢谢